Let’s say you work for a company and your manager is mad that there are pirated versions
假设你在一家公司工作，经理很生气有盗版版本
of your product out there. He tells you to secure their intellectual property and make
你的产品。他告诉你保护他们的知识产权
the program uncrackable. Is that possible? Last video I claimed that every program is
这个程序无法运行。有可能吗？最后一个视频我说每个程序
crackable. But that was old me. Maybe I learned more in the meantime, so let’s try it out.
易碎的但那是老我。也许我学会了在此期间，我们再试试看。
First problem is, that the license key was inside the binary. The simplest technique
第一个问题是，许可证密钥是在二进制文件中。最简单的技术
we had was to extract all strings and we found the key.
我们必须提取所有字符串，然后我们发现关键。
In the repository on github you can also find the source code of this simple license check.
在Github上的存储库中，您还可以找到此简单许可证检查的源代码。
So our first attempt to make this secure would be to not have the key inside. We can do this
所以我们第一次尝试确保安全不要把钥匙放在里面。我们可以做到这一点
by writing an algorithm that scrambles the key. You can come up with very creative ideas.
通过编写一个算法关键。你可以提出非常有创意的想法。
And then you can give your secured binary to a friend and ask him to crack it. Or write
然后你可以给你的安全二进制给一个朋友，让他破解它。或写
a keygen. That can be really fun. The first idea I have is to simply sum up
一个KEGEGEN。那真的很有趣。我的第一个想法是简单地总结
the ascii values of the key, and compare it to a magic value. So let’s modify the original
键的ASCII值，并进行比较一个魔法值。所以让我们修改原始的
program. First we have to define a new integer value that will store our calculated sum.
程序。首先，我们必须定义一个新的整数将存储计算出的和的值。
So int sum and set it to 0. Then we will add a for loop with the counter variable i, which
所以求和并设置为0。然后我们会补充带有计数器变量i的for循环，其中
starts at 0, with the loop condition that it continues to repeat this loop as long i
从0开始，循环条件为它继续重复这个循环，只要我
is smaller than the string length of the key that we can supply via argv[1]. And in each
小于键的字符串长度我们可以通过argv[1]供应。在每一个
repetition we will increment i by 1. Now we want to sum up the value of each character,
重复，我们将使i增加1。现在我们想要总结每个字符的值，
so sum += argv[1][i]. As you know a computer understands only numbers. So each character,
所以sum+=argv[1][i]。如你所知的计算机只懂数字。所以每个角色，
as you know from the ascii table, is a number. But the compiler knows, that argv is defined
正如您从ASCII表中所知道的，是一个数字。但是编译器知道，argv是被定义的
as a character sequence. So to not get any complaints we cast this value to an integer
作为一个字符序列。所以不能得到任何投诉我们将此值强制转换为整数
like that. Now we want to find out what the sum of our original key is. So let’s add
像那样。现在我们想知道我们原来的钥匙和是。所以让我们添加
a printf with %d in the format string and the sum as parameter. Now we can compile it
格式字符串中包含%d的printf和和作为参数。现在我们可以编译它了
and execute it with the original key. So here is the sum of all character values for this
并使用原始密钥执行。所以这里是此的所有字符值的总和
key. Let’s go to the code again and change the key check. We remove the string compare
关键。让我们再看一遍代码并更改关键检查。我们移除字符串比较
and replace it with a check that sum has to be that number.
用一张支票代替它就是那个数字。
Remove the debug printf and try it. So here it says that it’s a wrong key, and here
删除调试打印件并尝试。所以这里上面说钥匙错了，这里
it says that it is a correct key. Now try strings, and you will not find this key anymore.
它说它是一把正确的钥匙。现在尝试字符串，您将无法再找到此密钥。
How can we crack this now? Let’s open it with radare2. Analyse all,
我们现在怎么能破解这个？让我们用Radare2打开它。分析一切，
seek to the main function and print the disassembly. So let’s look for the Success or Fail message.
查找main 函数并打印拆卸。所以让我们来寻找成功或失败的信息。
Here it is. And then we can check where the branches are coming from to find the check
在这里。然后我们可以检查分支机构来找支票
if the license was correct or not. Ok so this compare and jump decides if we
如果许可证是否正确。好吧，这样比较和跳跃决定我们是否
print Access Granted or if we follow it Wrong. You can also see this hex value that is used
print Access授予或者如果我们遵循它错了。您还可以看到使用的此十六进制值
for the compare. I like to use python to convert between hex and decimal. So that’s exactly
比较。我喜欢使用python进行转换
what we have in our c code. So open the file again in debug mode and add
十六进制和十进制之间这就是确切的
a wrong license key. If we start the program it says it’s wrong. great. Now let’s set
我们在c代码中有什么。因此，在调试模式下再次打开文件并添加
a breakpoint with db at this one compare and reopen the file in debug mode. Now dc to continue.
错误的许可证密钥。如果我们启动该计划
Now we hit the breakpoint. with dr you can see that rip is at the jump. With dr rip=
它说这是错的。大。
we can set rip to the address we want to execute next. And obviously we want to print the success.
现在让我们来吧这个比较和db的断点
So we have cracked it again. Ok so we have found out, that if you can find
在调试模式下重新打开文件。现在直流继续。
this one compare where it is decided if you have a valid license or not, you can simply
现在我们点击了断点。和博士你可以
bypass it. But we are hackers, we love challenges. And
看到裂口在跳跃。用dr rip =
patching a jump is just boring. So let’s write a keygen.
我们可以设置rip到我们想要执行的地址下一个。
So first we have to reverse the algorithm. I will open the source code next to it, so
显然我们想要印刷成功。所以我们再次破解它。
we can compare. I Seek to main function. And enter visual mode.
好的，我们已经发现，如果你能找到的话这个比较你决定在哪里
Ok so we already know a little bit about this program from the other video. So here we can
你有没有有效的许可证，你可以简单绕过它。
see the compare if we have supplied a license key.
如果我们提供了许可证，请参阅比较键。
Then comes a printf. Like in our c code. After the printf we set the sum to 0. And also the
然后是printf。就像我们的c代码一样。
for loop is initialised with the index counter i to 0. And you can see that in the assembler
后printf我们将总和设置为0.还有
code to the left. Two addresses are set to 0 with a mov. And the address is calculated
for循环用索引计数器初始化我到0.你可以在汇编程序中看到它
with the base pointer address, that’s just another fancy register. And then the first
代码在左边。两个地址设置为
variable is at offset -0x18 from that, and the other one, well, radare replaced the number
0带有一个mov。并计算地址
with a name and calls it local_2_4 variable. But behind this name is just another number.
用基地指针地址，就是这样另一个花哨的注册。
Now when we look closely we can find a branch that loops back up. So those blocks here are
然后是第一个变量位于偏离-0x18的位置，并且
our for loop. And at the end of the for loop is a add instruction that adds 1 to this local
另一个，好吧，雷达取代了这个数字使用名称并将其称为local_2_4变量。
variable that was set 0 earlier. So that is the increment of i. And this local variable
但这个名字背后只是另一个数字。现在，仔细观察，我们可以找到一个分支
that radare identified is i. We can rename the variable with “afvn locale_2_4 i.
循环回来。那么这些块是
In this block we have a strlen call. And afterwards we compare two registers and it either continues
我们的循环。并在for循环结束时
with this main block or leaves. So that is the for loop condition here.
是一个添加指令，向本地添加1先前设置为0的变量。
Now comes a little bit of an ugly part if you have never seen this before. But if you
就是这样i的增量。
practice that it’s easy to see. Don’t worry if you get lost for the next minute.
而这个局部变量确定的雷达是我。
This just requires some practice. So first it loads a value from an address.
这只需要一些练习。所以首先它从地址加载一个值。
Which radare assigned a name to. This name came up before near the strlen. And if you
哪个radare分配了名称。这个名字
compare these two assembler blocks they are similar. You can see that it adds 8 to the
在strlen附近出现了。如果你
loaded value. So usually that means the value that was loaded is an address. Because we
比较这两个汇编程序块类似。
have 64bit, we often divide memory in 8 byte chunks.
你可以看到它增加了8负载值。
Imagine an array in memory, it might use multiple 8 byte chunks. The first chunk, which is the
所以通常这意味着价值加载的是一个地址。
first value in the array is simply there where the address points to. This means that if
因为我们有64位，我们经常将内存分成8个字节
you want to get the second value in the array you have to add 8 to the address. Now it points
块。想象一下内存中的数组，它可能会使用多个
to the 2nd array entry. So this is argv[1]. Remember we start counting at 0. So argv[0]
8个字节的块。第一块，也就是
would be the first array entry. argv is basically a variable that contains an address which
数组中的第一个值就在那里地址指向。
points to an array in memory. And this address is loaded into rax. And then we add 8 to it,
这意味着如果你想获得数组中的第二个值
to move it to the second entry in that array. Now this second entry itself is another address,
你必须在地址上加8。现在它指出
which is pointing to a string. In our assembler code we can see that the address of this string
到第二个数组条目。所以这是argv [1]。
is loaded, from the location rax is pointing to. Remember, the brackets around the register
记住我们从0开始计数。所以argv [0]将是第一个数组条目。
means, that the register contains an address and we access the value that is stored at
argv基本上是包含地址的变量
this address. Ok so rdx down here now has the address where
这个地址。好吧所以rdx在这里现在有地址在哪里
our string begins. Now we know that the next line loads the index counter i into eax. Each
我们的字符串开始现在我们知道了下一个
ascii character is 1 byte big. So similar how we can move an address to point to the
line将索引计数器i加载到eax中。每
next array entry by adding 8, we can move this string point to the next character by
ascii字符大1字节。如此相似
adding 1. So when we take the counter i, which might for example have the value 3, and add
我们如何移动地址指向通过添加8，下一个数组条目，我们可以移动
it to the address that points to the start of the string, it will then point to the 3rd
这个字符串指向下一个字符添加1.所以，当我们采取计数器i，哪个
character. Next we load 1 byte from the current address in rax. This is the value of this
可能例如具有值3，并添加它指向开始的地址
particular character. And then we add this value in eax to a local variable at offset
然后它将指向第3个字符串字符。
-0x18 which we earlier set to 0. So this is our sum! Whoa. I know it seems tedious and
接下来我们从当前加载1个字节在rax中的地址。
confusing. And crazy. But if you do this a couple of times, and also debug this step
这就是价值特别的性格。
by step with gdb, and look at your registers in each step and inspect the memory addresses
然后我们添加这个eax中的值到偏移量的局部变量
it becomes clear. So now we know that this is a loop, that goes over each character of
-0x18我们之前设置为0.所以这是我们的总和！
the string and adds the character values to a variable. Now when the strlen compare branch
哇。我知道这似乎很乏味
goes the other way, we leave the loop and the sum is compared to hex 0x394. Cool!
混乱。和疯狂。
If your brain turned off during the previous part, Turn in ON again. let’s do this again
但如果你这样做了几次，还调试这一步
but thismtime you can ignore most of the stuff again and work backwards with educated guesses.
但是这个时候你可以忽略大部分的东西再次通过有根据的猜测向后工作。
So you see that this address gets compared with a certain value. So look where this value
所以你看到这个地址被比较了具有一定的价值。
came from. Ahh it has to do something with this add. Now you can reload the binary in
那么看看这个价值所在来自。
debug mode with ood. I will use ABCD as an example key. Press p to display the addresses,
啊，它必须做点什么这个补充。
place a breakpoint. Then use V! to switch to fancy mode. And then execute it. Now always
现在您可以重新加载二进制文件了调试模式与ood。
continue with :dc and look at the register rax that gets added. So in the first loop
我将使用ABCD作为示例键。
its 0x41. If you know your ascii table you know that this is a capital A. You can also
按p显示地址，放置一个断点。
use Python as a handy tool to convert back and forth. And next time it's 0x42, that is
然后用V！换成
a Capital B. And then it’s 0x43. So it clearly just Iterates over the supplied string. See,
花哨的模式。然后执行它。
now you know that happens, without having to read assembler line by line.
现在总是继续：dc并查看寄存器
So let’s recreate this in python. Let’s write a function called check key.
rax被添加。所以在第一个循环中
It takes a key as parameter. Now we define a character sum and set it to 0. Then we loop
它的0x41。如果你知道你的ascii表
over all characters with for c in key. Then we add the ascii value to the sum with ord
知道这是大都会A.你也可以使用Python作为转换回来的便利工具
of c. Then we print the current key and it’s sum.
来回。下次是0x42，就是这样
Then we return the sum. Now let’s do some example keys. With yy
一个资本B.然后它是0x43。所以很清楚
you can copy a line. And with p you can paste it again. I deliberately use A, B, C, D because
你可以复制一行。用P可以粘贴再说一遍。我故意用A，B，C，D是因为
their numerical value always increases by 1.
它们的数值总是增加 1.
Cool. You can see how the sum is always 1 bigger than the previous one. Now let’s
酷。你可以看到总和总是1。比前一个大。现在让我们
use a very naiv randomized keygen to try different keys, until we find one. This can be obviously
使用非常NAIV的随机keygen尝试不同的钥匙，直到我们找到一把。很明显
made much more intelligentlt, because of the linear behaviour of this function. But it
使之更加智能化，因为此函数的线性行为。但它
will still look cool. So import random module and create a endless
仍然看起来很酷。所以导入随机模块并创建一个无止境的
loop. Our key starts with an empty string. Now we
循环。我们的密钥以空字符串开始。现在我们
select a random character from an alphabet with random choice and append it to the key.
从字母表中选择一个随机字符随机选择并将其附加到密钥。
Now we check this key. If this key’s sum is already too big, we reset the key and start
现在我们检查一下这把钥匙。如果这把钥匙是和已经太大了，我们重新设置键，然后开始
fresh. And if we hit the correct value, we print this key.
新鲜的。如果我们达到正确的值，我们打印此密钥。
I will modify the print in the check_key function to make it look cooler.
我将在检查键功能中修改打印让它看起来更酷。
Now save it and run it. Oops… something is wroong… Ah… I had the compare the wrong
现在保存并运行它。哎呀……什么东西是不是……啊……我比较错了
way around. We reset the key when it’s already too big. Ok now…
绕道而行。我们重置了钥匙太大了。好吧…
DAMN that is fast. Even though it’s a very bad algorithm, we quickly find many many keys.
他妈的太快了。即使它是一个非常算法不好，我们很快就能找到很多密钥。
Let’s see if they work. Oh yes they work! Cool, huh?
让我们看看它们是否有效。哦，是的，他们工作！很酷，是吧？
So we have learned now, that we can hide licence keys by using an algorithm to verify if a
所以我们现在知道了，我们可以隐藏许可证密钥通过使用算法来验证是否
key is valid. This whole algorithm becomes useless when we find the assembler code that
密钥有效。整个算法变成了
decides if it was valid or not. In our case it’s a simple compare/jump that we can patch.
当我们找到汇编代码时没用决定它是否有效。
Obviously you can make that a bit more complex, for example doing a license key check in different
在我们的例子中这是一个简单的比较/跳转，我们可以修补。
places. But generally that’s how you can defeat that.
显然你可以让它更复杂一点，例如，执行不同的许可证密钥检查
Now if we like a challenge, or we don’t want to patch a binary, because whatever,
地方。但通常你就是这样
there are many reasons for why you might want a valid key. We can use static analysis and
打败那个。现在，如果我们喜欢挑战，或者我们不喜欢
reverse engineer the license check algorithm and write a keygen to generate valid keys.
想修补二进制文件，因为无论如何，你可能想要的原因有很多
Obviously this algorithm also can become very complex, but generally if you put a lot of
一个有效的密钥。我们可以使用静态分析和
work in it, you can figure it out. Now you tell that to your manager, but he
逆向工程许可证检查算法并写一个keygen来生成有效的密钥。
is a smart ass and tells you: “then stop people from being able to reverse engineer
显然这个算法也可以变得非常复杂，但一般如果你把很多
the binary”. Then you drag yourself back to the desk and you come up with a new creative
在其中工作，你可以搞清楚。现在你告诉你的经理，但他
how to stop somebody from debugging and reversing it
是一个自作聪明，告诉你："然后停下来